Let the Best Species Win
Cowboys vs. Dinosaurs is a science fiction, action,
western film directed by Ari Novak.
After an accidental explosion at a local mine, dinosaurs emerge
from the rubble to terrorize a small western town.
Now, a group of gunslingers must defend their home if anyone is going
to survive in a battle of cowboys versus dinosaurs.
Marcus, played by Vernon Wells.
Val Walker, played by Rib Hillis.
Sky, played by Casey Fitzgerald.
Henry, played by John Freeman.
Quaid, played by Kelcey Watson.
Dr. Sinclair, played by Sara Malakul Lane.
The Good Dinosaur is a 2015 American animated comedy-drama adventure film
produced by Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures.
The film was directed by Peter Sohn and produced by Denise Ream, from a screenplay written by Meg
LeFauve, who also wrote the film's story with Sohn, Bob Peterson, Kelsey Mann, and Erik Benson.
It stars the voices of Raymond Ochoa, Jack Bright,
Steve Zahn, Sam Elliott, Anna Paquin, A.
Buckley, Jeffrey Wright, and Frances McDormand.
The film explores an alternate history where non-avian dinosaurs never became extinct, following a young, timid Apatosaurus named Arlo (Ochoa) living on a farm with his family, who
meets an unlikely human friend named Spot (Bright) while traveling through a dangerous and mysterious landscape in order to return home, after being washed downriver.
Development of The Good Dinosaur began with Peterson and Sohn working on the film in 2009, when the former came up with the
idea of exploring what dinosaurs represent in the present day and how they are represented in stereotypes.
The project was officially announced in 2011, with the release date, plot, director
and co-director, producer, and other small details being revealed.
During its production, the team encountered various problems, which led to
multiple story revisions, as well as changing directors and voice cast.
To create a realistic background for the film, the team traveled to various
American landscapes, which were later incorporated into the film.
Arlo is designed to look distinct and relatable, in
order to connect with audiences.
In addition, the film pays homage to the Western genre in its themes,
character representation, and western North American landscapes.
Mychael and Jeff Danna composed the film's musical score, marking
Pixar's first film to be scored by two composers.
The Good Dinosaur premiered on November 10, 2015, in Paris, and was released in the United States on November 25 in the Disney Digital 3-D and RealD 3D
formats, marking the first time where two Pixar films were released in the same year, following the release of Inside Out earlier that year.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics for its animation and themes,
though its storytelling was not considered to be up to Pixar's standards.
It became Pixar's first box office failure, grossing $332.2 million on a $175–200
million budget, and losing the studio an estimated $85 million.
The film received a nomination for Best Animated Feature
Film at the 73rd Golden Globe Awards.
The film explores themes of small town, montana,
tyrannosaurus rex, animal attack, nuclear radiation.
The tone is thought_provoking.